{
    "id": "2766d86e5b6a4727af06d99b1ab56bc0",
    "title": "Gap Filling Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "………………………… your shoes off.",
            "description": "The simple present is used in imperative sentence.",
            "answers": [
                "Take",
                "Taking",
                "Takes"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She ……………………………. younger than her elder sister.",
            "description": "We use the simple present to talk about facts.",
            "answers": [
                "look",
                "is looking",
                "looks"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "How did you ………………………… then?",
            "description": "The infinitive without to is used after do, does and did.",
            "answers": [
                "react",
                "reacts",
                "reacted"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………… forget to close the door when you leave.",
            "description": "The simple present is used in imperative sentences. In imperatives the subject is you.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "Don't",
                "Doesn't"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The cop asked him what he ………………………………… doing there.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, we use a past tense in the subordinate clause as well.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………… my mother every day.",
            "description": "Use the simple present to talk about habits. ",
            "answers": [
                "call",
                "calls",
                "am calling"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The cat ……………………………. her litter.",
            "description": "Has had is in the present perfect tense. The present perfect is used to give news.",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "had",
                "has had",
                "had has"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "They ………………………….. by now.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will leave",
                "will have left",
                "had left"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If we do not take precautions, we …………………………….. in trouble.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "would be",
                "will be",
                "would have been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………………. her since our school days.",
            "description": "We use the present perfect to talk about life experiences up to now.",
            "answers": [
                "knew",
                "know",
                "have known"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Somebody wanted a drink, …………………………….?",
            "description": "They is used in question tags after somebody, anybody, nobody. ",
            "answers": [
                "did they",
                "didn't they",
                "didn't somebody"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I would rather you …………………………… talking to her.",
            "description": "The past tense is used in this construction. ",
            "answers": [
                "stopped",
                "stop",
                "have stopped"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}